

SUMMARY

For 9+ years, I have facilitated end-to-end UX processes where I closely partner with product management, engineering, and user research. Sensitive to aesthetic and cognitive principles, I can concretely express my product hypotheses with stakeholders through rapid coding via frontend technologies. With my diverse skills and holistic thinking, I have led design efforts across platforms for a wide array of problem domains: natural language, mobile search, editorial design, publishing, digital advertising, and infrastructural engineering.

EXPERIENCE

Nov 2015 - Present

Sr. Designer/Prototyper, Search

Yahoo, Sunnyvale

Currently designing and prototyping for multimodal experiences including an Alexa Sports Skill, partnering with product, engineering, science, and research; Automating experiments with ASK CLI and AWS

Facilitating UX studies for search experiences across desktop and mobile web; led the design of a nascent Al platform to streamline chatbot development

O Mar 2014 - Nov 2015

Sr. Designer/Prototyper, Media

Yahoo, Sunnyvale

Organized concept and design experimentation for "communities around content" org strategy; led desktop and mobile web prototyping efforts for Yahoo homepage and media vertical experiences

O Dec 2012 - Mar 2014

Designer/Prototyper, Platforms AdUX

Yahoo, Sunnyvale

Designed and prototyped various responsive ad units; co-developed web frontend for experimental responsive ad platform concept

O June 2009 - Dec 2012

Interaction Designer, Developer Products

Yahoo, Sunnyvale

Owned design language and implementation across various infrastructural engineering teams; created first design culture in an engineering-focused organization * Converted from intern to full-time employee

O Summer 2008

Software Engineering Intern

Apple, Cupertino

O Summer 2007

Software Engineering Intern

Hewlett-Packard, Cupertino

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

O Design and Prototyping Tools

Sketch HTML/CSS (SASS/LESS)

Zeplin JavaScript, Node.js

Craft Framer, CoffeeScript

Adobe Photoshop Alexa Skills Kit CLI, AWS Lambda

Adobe Illustrator Twitter Bootstrap, Yeoman

Keynote Python

Git/GitHub

jQuery, d3, React

O Design Methodology

OmniGraffle

Hypotheses Scenarios

Competitive Analysis Flow Diagrams

Contextual Inquiry Wireframes

Generative Studies Visual Mocks

Heuristic Evaluations Visual Style Guides

Usability Testing Rapid Prototyping

Card Sorting

PUBLIC SPEAKING

0

Stanford Digital Media Academy 2016

Invited as a role model and guest instructor for various youth groups (e.g. ages 8-17) taking coding bootcamp classes; advised Made by Girls participants interested in STEM fields

O Yahoo User Interface Conference 2013

Gave a talk on prototyping methodology inspired by LEGO building principles to frontend engineers across the tech industry

EDUCATION

B.S. in Computer Science 2009

California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo